Grief can be a funny thing.
My Dead Friend Zoe is a comedy, war, drama film
directed by Kyle Hausmann-Stokes.
Merit, a U.S.
Army veteran suffering from PTSD, is repeatedly tortured by
visions of her deceased friend and company buddy Zoe.
After her Afghanistan service in 2016, she attends group therapy until Dale, her
grandfather and former Lieutenant Colonel, is recently diagnosed with Alzheimer's.
Merit steps up to his aide, and discovers more about herself and her family, while
also gaining the courage to put her metaphorical demons to rest.
Merit, played by Sonequa Martin-Green.
Zoe, played by Natalie Morales.
Dale, played by Ed Harris.
Dr. Cole, played by Morgan Freeman.
Alex, played by Utkarsh Ambudkar.
Kris, played by Gloria Reuben.
My Dead Friend Zoe is a 2024 American comedy-drama film
written by Kyle Hausmann-Stokes and A.
Bermudez, directed by Hausmann-Stokes and starring Sonequa Martin-Green, Natalie
Morales, Gloria Reuben, Utkarsh Ambudkar, Morgan Freeman, and Ed Harris.
It premiered at South by Southwest on March 9, 2024 (winning the Audience Award), and
was theatrically released in the United States on February 28, 2025.
The film explores themes of army, post-traumatic stress
disorder (ptsd), support group, date, afghanistan.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.